# **Gourav Dash**

FullStack developer/ Backend Developer

gourav.dash92@gmail.com

LINKED IN - GOURAV DASH

# **ABOUT ME**

A software developer with 7+ years of experience with .NET technologies for creating web and desktop based, reliable and scalable applications. Experienced in healthcare, stock management, government and E-commerce domain applications. Intrigued in ,Net Core and Azure based software development with a fascination for Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.

## SKILLS

Languages: C#, C, C++, TypeScript, Javascript

Framework: .Net, ASP.Net, RestAPI, WCF,

WPF, .Net Core, Angular, React

Database/Cloud: SQL, Azure

# **PROJECTS**

#### Conduent

Technology:.Net, C#, SQL, Entity Framework, RestAPI

Digital Processing of Healthcare documents, Restful applications development, Security framework design, Atomic Crud operations, scalable application

#### **Business Automation of Markfed**

Technology: .Net Core, Angular, Azure, WCF

Designed and Developed large scale reliable and open source applications for real-time tracking of stock movement, comprehensive report generation, Developed medium for encryption and transfer of sensitive information.

## **EDUCATION**

2010-2014

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATION

#### Biju Patnaik University of Technology

Relevant Courses - C Programming, Data Structures & Algorithms (C), OOPS Concepts (C++), Operating Systems

2014-2014

.NET FRAMEWORK CERTIFICATION

### **Interface Software Solutions**

.Net Framework certification and experience in live project developing applications using Restful API and SQL Server.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

NOV 2021-PRESENT

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### INFINITE COMPUTER SOLUTIONS

Designed scalable and reusable applications to digitally process healthcare related documents.

Developed viewer for comprehensive and clean reports.

June 2017- July 2020

#### **PROGRAMMER**

#### **DEPARTMENT OF COOPERATION, ODISHA**

Designed and Developed large scale reliable and open source applications for real-time tracking of stock movement, comprehensive report generation, application security, prevented cascading failures

May 2014- June 2017

### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

#### **3S INFO SOLUTIONS**

Designed and Developed web and windows applications using identity authentication and authorization in various domain like E-Commerce, Public Service, Government.

Developed SOAP based app in goods transport service

# Skills



## HOBBY

- CODING
   KARATE
- READING
   TRAVELING
- GAMING